Hello my name is David Brown and this is a pronunciation class. Hi David. I'm
안녕하세요, 제 이름은 데이비드 브라운이고 이 수업은 발음 수업입니다. 안녕하세요, 데이비드 선생님. 저는
fine thank you. How are you? I'm doing great. Thank you. Thank you. Welcome. Thank
잘 지내요, 감사합니다. 선생님은 어떠신가요? 저는 아주 잘 지내고 있습니다. 감사합니다. 감사합니다. 환영합니다.
Thank you, David. Are you ready for your lesson today? Yes. All right. All right. Well we
감사합니다, 데이비드 선생님. 오늘 수업 준비되셨나요? 네. 좋습니다. 좋습니다. 그럼 우리가
can practice this lesson that I see that you selected. We have this short
선택하신 이 수업 내용을 연습해 볼 수 있겠네요. 우리는 이 짧은
i sound and then this long e sound the short i sound is like /ɪ/ and then the
i 소리와 그리고 이 긴 e 소리가 있습니다. 짧은 i 소리는 /ɪ/와 같고, 그리고
long e sound is like /iː/, right? Okay. This is important for us to master because it
긴 e 소리는 /iː/와 같습니다, 그렇죠? 네. 이것은 우리가 숙달하는 것이 중요합니다. 왜냐하면
can cause confusion for native English speakers and it's a really
영어 원어민에게 혼란을 야기할 수 있고, 이것은 정말로
commonly mispronounced pair. So we have some examples here. Some funny
흔하게 잘못 발음되는 쌍이기 때문입니다. 그래서 여기 몇 가지 예시가 있습니다. 재미있는
examples. We have fill and feel, sit and seat, chip and
예시들이죠. fill과 feel, sit과 seat, chip과
cheap. This one is bit. This one is beat, beat, ship and this one is sheep. This
cheap이 있습니다. 이것은 bit입니다. 이것은 beat, beat, ship이고 이것은 sheep입니다. 이것은
is lid and this one is lead. All right. So we need to know the difference
lid이고 이것은 lead입니다. 네. 그래서 우리는 /ɪ/ 소리와
between the /ɪ/ sound and the /iː/ sound, the /ɪ/ sound and the /iː/ sound. Okay. The
/iː/ 소리, /ɪ/ 소리와 /iː/ 소리의 차이를 알아야 합니다. 네.
short /ɪ/ versus the /iː/ sounds. So this is what we'll practice in today's lesson. Two
짧은 /ɪ/ 대 /iː/ 소리입니다. 이것이 오늘 수업에서 연습할 내용입니다. 두 가지
different sounds. For example, what is this? This is ship*, ship, very good. And this
다른 소리죠. 예를 들어, 이것은 무엇일까요? 이것은 ship*, ship, 아주 좋습니다. 그리고 이것은,
one, these are, these are sheep. These are sheep, right? Regular plural noun. So we're
이것들은 sheep입니다. 이것들은 sheep이죠, 그렇죠? 규칙 복수 명사입니다. 그래서 우리는
looking at two English sounds that can be a little bit tricky but are very, very
약간 까다로울 수 있지만 명확한 발음을 위해 매우, 매우 중요한 두 가지 영어 소리를
important for clear speaking. We want to understand and be understood and this can
살펴보고 있습니다. 우리는 이해하고 이해받기를 원하며 이것은 우리의
impact our comprehension. So it can change the meaning of words. We have this one
이해력에 영향을 미칠 수 있습니다. 그래서 단어의 의미를 바꿀 수 있죠. 우리는 이것,
which is ship and this one which is cheap and that is just one example. So today we
ship이 있고, 이것, cheap이 있습니다. 이것은 단지 하나의 예시일 뿐입니다. 그래서 오늘 우리는
have two objectives here. I'd like for you to listen to these objectives. Today you
여기 두 가지 목표가 있습니다. 이 목표들을 들어보셨으면 합니다. 오늘 여러분은
will learn to hear the difference between /ɪ/ and /iː/ and say /ɪ/ and /iː/ more clearly. Let's
/ɪ/와 /iː/의 차이를 듣는 법을 배우고, /ɪ/와 /iː/를 더 명확하게 말하는 법을 배울 것입니다. 이것을
try this. Can you repeat it for me? /ɪ/. Now, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/. Awesome. And so we have a little
시도해 봅시다. 저를 따라 반복해주시겠어요? /ɪ/. 이제, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/. 멋지네요. 그래서 우리는 연습을 위한 작은
activity here to practice. I said that you would need something like a stick and something
활동이 여기 있습니다. 제가 막대기 같은 것과 블록 같은 것이
like a block. So I have a colored pencil and one of my daughter's blocks. Do you have
필요하다고 말씀드렸죠. 그래서 저는 색연필과 제 딸의 블록 중 하나를 가지고 있습니다. 무언가
something? Okay, yes, yes, I have something. Okay, okay, like this. Alright, so let's
가지고 계신가요? 네, 네, 저도 뭔가 있어요. 네, 네, 이런 거요. 좋습니다, 그럼
imagine that we have the /ɪ/ sound and it's like tapping a block. Okay, right? So tap /ɪ/
/ɪ/ 소리가 있고 그것이 블록을 두드리는 것과 같다고 상상해봅시다. 네, 그렇죠? 그럼 /ɪ/ 하면서
your block, say /ɪ/. Now we have the /iː/ sound which is longer. You can imagine that you have
블록을 두드려보세요, /ɪ/라고 말해보세요. 이제 더 긴 /iː/ 소리가 있습니다. 여러분이 연필을 가지고
your pencil and you're dragging it against something, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/. Good, /iː/. Alright, so
무언가에 대고 끄는 것을 상상할 수 있습니다, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/. 좋습니다, /iː/. 네, 그럼
listen again, /ɪ/, /ɪ/ /iː/, /iː/. Notice that your jaw changes. So you have your tongue in a position
다시 들어보세요, /ɪ/, /ɪ/ /iː/, /iː/. 턱이 변하는 것을 주목하세요. 혀가 입안에서
of your mouth higher for one than the other. It's all about the position of your tongue
하나의 소리보다 다른 소리에서 더 높은 위치에 있습니다. 이것은 모두 입안에서의 혀의 위치에
in your mouth, /iː/ sound versus the /ɪ/, which is a little bit more relaxed. Okay. Do you hear
관한 것입니다, /iː/ 소리 대 /ɪ/ 소리, /ɪ/는 조금 더 편안합니다. 네. 차이가
the difference? Yes. Okay, excellent. So the short i, the /ɪ/ sound is a little bit
들리시나요? 네. 네, 훌륭합니다. 그래서 짧은 i, /ɪ/ 소리는 /iː/ 소리와
different than the /iː/ sound, the /iː/ is more, and it's /iː/ with the tongue higher up. We have
조금 다릅니다. /iː/는 더 그렇고, 혀가 더 위로 올라간 상태에서 /iː/입니다. 우리는
the /ɪ/ sound with the jaw lower down, /iː/, you see my mouth, /iː/, alright? Okay, now you
턱이 더 아래로 내려간 상태에서 /ɪ/ 소리가 납니다, /iː/, 제 입 모양 보이시죠, /iː/, 그렇죠? 네, 이제
don't want to say /ɛ/, and this is, we have the /ɛ/ sounds like lead (metal), and we have the /ɪ/ sound
/ɛ/라고 말하고 싶지 않으실 겁니다. 그리고 이것은, 우리는 lead (금속)처럼 /ɛ/ 소리가 있고, lid처럼 /ɪ/ 소리가
like lid, and then we have the /iː/ sound like lead (to guide). And all of this depends on the position
있고, 그리고 lead (이끌다)처럼 /iː/ 소리가 있습니다. 그리고 이 모든 것은 입안에서의 혀의 위치에
of your tongue in your mouth. We have /ɛ/, /ɪ/, and /iː/. Repeat after me, /ɛ/, /ɪ/, /iː/   /ɛ/, /ɪ/, /iː/
따라 다릅니다. 우리는 /ɛ/, /ɪ/, 그리고 /iː/가 있습니다. 저를 따라 반복하세요, /ɛ/, /ɪ/, /iː/   /ɛ/, /ɪ/, /iː/
/iː/. Very good. Alright, so there are some differences in these sounds depending on the position
/iː/. 아주 좋습니다. 네, 그래서 혀나 턱의 위치에 따라 이 소리들에는
of your tongue or jaw. So your mouth needs to be a little bit more open than with the
몇 가지 차이점이 있습니다. 그래서 입을 스페인어의 /i/보다 조금 더 벌려야 합니다.
/i/ in Spanish. Your lips are relaxed, not smiling and not tight. So with the /ɪ/, it's like
입술은 편안하게, 웃는 모양도 아니고 꽉 다문 모양도 아닙니다. 그래서 /ɪ/의 경우, 이것은
this little bit more and it is just /ɪ/, /ɪ/, right? Not /ɛ/. The tongue is a little high, a
조금 더 그렇고, 그냥 /ɪ/, /ɪ/입니다, 그렇죠? /ɛ/가 아니고요. 혀는 약간 높고, 약간
little to the front, and you'll need to relax your tongue a little. And it's a quick, a short
앞쪽에 있고, 혀를 약간 편안하게 해야 합니다. 그리고 이것은 빠르고, 짧은
quick sound like a little tap in the block sound, right? Okay. Feel it, relaxed. So try
빠른 소리입니다, 마치 블록을 가볍게 두드리는 소리처럼요, 그렇죠? 네. 느껴보세요, 편안하게. 그럼
making this sound yourself. You can mute it. Try making this sound yourself again. Let
이 소리를 직접 내보세요. 음소거하셔도 됩니다. 이 소리를 다시 한번 직접 내보세요.
me hear you. Okay, /ɪ/, /iː/ And then /ɪ/, and /iː/, very good. Excellent. Okay. Alright.
한번 들어볼게요. 네, /ɪ/, /iː/ 그리고 /ɪ/, 그리고 /iː/, 아주 좋습니다. 훌륭해요. 네. 좋습니다.
And just a little bit of this practice can make a big difference. So now I want you to
그리고 이 연습을 조금만 해도 큰 차이를 만들 수 있습니다. 자 이제 저에게
show me... you can use a mirror or you can use the camera too. If you're too shy to use the
보여주세요... 거울을 사용하셔도 되고 카메라도 사용하셔도 됩니다. 카메라 사용이 너무 부끄러우시다면,
camera, that's okay if you want to use a mirror. So look at your mouth in the camera.
거울을 사용하셔도 괜찮습니다. 그럼 카메라로 자신의 입 모양을 보세요.
Okay. Like this. You can see /ɪ/, /ɪ/, /ɪ/, /ɪ/, not /ɛ/, but /ɪ/... /ɪ/ , and /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, perfect.
네. 이렇게요. /ɪ/, /ɪ/, /ɪ/, /ɪ/, /ɛ/가 아니라 /ɪ/... /ɪ/ , 그리고 /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, 완벽합니다.
Alright, so you have the mouth, which has the lips spread wide, like a rubber band, for
네, 그래서 입술이 고무줄처럼 넓게 벌어진 입 모양이 있습니다,
the /iː/ sounds, and it's high into the front, and you can feel a little bit of tension. So
/iː/ 소리가 나는 곳이죠, 그리고 혀는 높고 앞쪽에 있으며, 약간의 긴장을 느낄 수 있습니다. 그래서
we have the, this one, which is the /iː/ sound, this is /ɪt/, and this one is /iːt/, right? Right.
우리는, 이것, 즉 /iː/ 소리, 이것은 /ɪt/이고, 이것은 /iːt/입니다, 그렇죠? 맞아요.
It's a long, stretch sound, like pulling something. So you can imagine for the /iː/ sound
이것은 길고, 늘어지는 소리입니다, 마치 무언가를 당기는 것처럼요. 그래서 /iː/ 소리를 낼 때
that you have, like rubber bands pulling in the corner of your mouth for this one.
입꼬리에 고무줄을 당기는 것처럼 상상할 수 있습니다.
So you can see this in the image here. You have the, /ɪ/ sounds here, which is the center
여기 이미지에서 이것을 볼 수 있습니다. 여기 /ɪ/ 소리가 있는데, 이것은 중앙
in the front. The jaw is mid to close, and it's relaxed. And then the /iː/ sound is more spread
앞쪽에 있습니다. 턱은 중간에서 닫힌 상태이고, 편안합니다. 그리고 /iː/ 소리는 더 벌어져
apart. It's a little bit more closed, and the tongue is a little higher up. That's a
있습니다. 조금 더 닫혀 있고, 혀는 약간 더 위로 올라가 있습니다.
good job. Alright, so let's practice some of these. Here's an activity for us. You've got
잘하셨어요. 네, 그럼 이것들 중 일부를 연습해봅시다. 여기 우리를 위한 활동이 있습니다. 여러분은
your block and your pencil or pen, or whatever, or stick. Okay. So when you, when I say,
블록과 연필이나 펜, 또는 뭐든지, 막대기를 가지고 계시죠. 네. 그럼 여러분이, 제가 말할 때,
or when, and when you say a word that has this short /ɪ/ sound, I want you to tap the block.
또는, 그리고 여러분이 이 짧은 /ɪ/ 소리가 들어간 단어를 말할 때, 블록을 두드리시기 바랍니다.
Okay. And then when it has a long /iː/ sound, and then I want you to slide your stick. You ready?
네. 그리고 긴 /iː/ 소리가 날 때는, 막대기를 미끄러뜨리시기 바랍니다. 준비되셨나요?
I'm ready. All right. So ship. Repeat, ship, ship.
준비됐습니다. 네. 그럼 ship. 반복하세요, ship, ship.
Uh-huh. Ship. Ship. Get. Bed. Bed. Beats. Beats. Ship. Ship. And ship.
네. Ship. Ship. Get. Bed. Bed. Beats. Beats. Ship. Ship. 그리고 ship.
Sheep. Good. Sit. Good. Fill. Feel. Feel. Good. All right. We can practice a little bit more with this
Sheep. 좋습니다. Sit. 좋습니다. Fill. Feel. Feel. 좋습니다. 네. 이 /ɪ/ 소리로 조금 더 연습할 수 있습니다.
/ɪ/ sound.
/ɪ/ 소리요.